（回波探头）
（MU/TH/UR 9001苏醒中）
（2142年2月9日）
（位置：网罟座泽塔二星系统）
（任务目标 范围内）
（拦截倒数）
（威兰企业）
（目标已取得）
（返回程序已启动）
《异形：罗穆路斯》
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
全体员工注意…
Attention all workers. Attention all workers.
日班将在15分钟后开始
Day shift starting in T-minus 15 minutes.
农民立刻至食堂报到
Farmers to report to mess hall immediately.
如果出现任何症状 如发烧 咳嗽
If you are experiencing any symptoms, such as fever, cough…
呕吐或呼吸困难
vomiting, or difficulty breathing…
请至医疗区检查
proceed to the medical bay for examination.
殖民地安全与福祉是威兰的第一考量
The safety and well-being of our colony is Weyland-Yutani's top priority.
全体员工注意…
Attention all workers…
听说过有幽闭恐惧症的太空人吗
Did you hear about the claustrophobic astronaut?
他需要空间
He needed space.
我求你别讲了
I'm begging you, you got to stop.
我把钱都花在一条不合的皮带上
I just spent my full share on a belt that won't fit.
我好浪「肥」
Huge waist.
玉米面包给我
See that cornbread.
因为我「实务」经验丰富
Maybe it's 'cause I'm on this seafood diet.
看到食物就吃
I see food, I eat it.
好冷哦
That's so bad.
你以前听到都会笑
You always laughed at that one.
那是我12岁的时候
Yeah, when I was 12.
一定是芬奇先生
I'm sure it's Mr. Finch.
今天就欠他三个月了
We owe him three months today.
他会再打来
He'll call again.
到时我们可能不在这里了
Well, maybe we won't be here when he does.
安迪 跟紧一点
Andy. Stay close to me.
清醒 快清醒
Wake up. Wake up now.
我们都是威兰的奴隶
We're all Weyland-Yutani slaves.
公司供我们吃住 却要我们的命
The company pays us with food and shelter and takes our lives in exchange.
（杰克森星采矿殖民地 人口2781）
（距地球65光年 每年日照时数0）
别相信他们的谎言
Don't believe their lies.
他们掌控了你
They own you!
安迪…
Andy, Andy. Hey, hey, hey.
过来
Hey, Andy. Come on. Come on.
我做了什么 -那是诈骗
- What did I do? - It's a scam.
球绝不会在你选的杯子底下
The ball is never under the cup that you pick.
那是诈术
It's a trick.
但我要怎么赚钱
But how am I gonna get the money?
什么钱
Money for what?
我们到伊瓦加星买马的钱
To pay for the horse when we get to Yvaga.
你要买马
You're gonna get a horse?
我想叫它雨迪
I wanna call it Raindy.
你懂吗
Do you get it?
雨迪 -我喜欢 很棒
- Raindy. - No, I like it. Yeah, it's good.
你去那边等
Okay, so you just wait over there.
我可能要一下子
Okay, I might be a minute.
（殖民事务处）
别惹麻烦 好吗
Stay out of trouble, all right?
全体员工都将获得照顾
All employees will be seen.
祝你好运
Good luck.
请依序排队
Line up in an orderly fashion.
下一位
Next.
请问全名和职业
Full name and occupation, please.
玛丽雨恩卡拉定 务农
Marie Raines Carradine, ma'am. Farming.
我来申请旅行文件
It's about my travel papers.
（达到额度：可转移）
我达到额度 应该能离开了
I met my quota, and I should be free to go now.
对吧
Right?
去哪
Go where?
伊瓦加星
Yvaga.
它是独立系统 但已完全地球化
It's an independent system, but it's fully terraformed.
那里看得见太阳
You can actually see the sun out there.
你的父母呢
Where are your parents?
三个周期前去世了
They died three cycles ago.
因为采矿罹患肺病
Lung disease, from the mines.
现在只剩我和我弟
It's just me and my brother now.
他们贩卖希望 使我们甘愿为奴…
They sell us hope to keep us slaves.
他们贩卖希望
They sell us hope to keep us slaves. Wake up now.
抱歉 你还没有资格解约
I'm sorry, but you're not eligible for contract release yet.
因为缺工 你要被转到矿区
Due to a shortage of workers, you're being transferred to the mines.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
不对 我达到要求时数了
No, no, no, I reached the required hours.
你们必须让我走
You have to let me go.
（殖民工作合约）
可惜额度提高到两万四千小时
Unfortunately, quotas have been raised to 24,000 hours…
你再过五到六年才能解约
so you'll be released from contract in another five to six years.
谢谢 别忘了公司非常感谢…
Thank you, and remember the company is really grateful…
你的持续贡献
for your ongoing service.
小雨 -喂
- Rain! - Hey!
住手
Hey, stop!
放开他 混蛋
Get off him! You bastards!
我在这里
I got you, I got you.
糟糕 你流血了
Shit, you're bleeding.
好
Okay.
你没事
You're okay.
我把你重置
I'm resetting you.
我帮你
I got you.
没事
It's okay.
我不该让你落单的
I shouldn't have left you alone.
他们贩卖希望 使我们甘愿为奴…
They sell us hope to keep us slaves.
醒醒吧  你们就是奴隶
Wake up now. They own you.
嗨 小雨
Hi, Rain.
抱歉我整天一直打给你
Look, I'm sorry. I know I've been calling you all day…
因为有事情 应该让你知道
but, look, something's come up, and I think you should know about it.
到拖车这边来 带上安迪
So, come by the trailers and bring Andy.
嗨
Hey.
拜…
Oh, for…
游戏结束
Game over, man.
小雨 好久不见
Sup, Rain? Long time no see.
我就说她会出现
I told you she'd show up.
你欠我五块钱
You owe me five bucks.
安迪
Andy!
盲眼矿工怎么会掉进井里
Why'd the blind miner fall down the well?
为什么
Why?
因为他有点瞎
'Cause he couldn't see that well.
拜托别怂恿他
Please don't encourage him.
进去吧 我马上过去
All right, go inside. I'll be there in a second.
小凯 -小雨
- Kay. - Rain.
嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi!
嗨
Hi.
我好想你
I missed you.
我知道我哥也很想你
And I know my brother missed you, too.
真高兴你来了
I'm really glad you came.
我听说了你们爸爸的事
I heard about your dad.
真的很遗憾
I'm really sorry.
在每个周期的雹暴和新疾病之间…
Well, between the hailstorms and the new diseases every cycle…
对 大家都快死了
Yeah, everybody's dying, right?
该给她看吗
So, should we show her?
给我看什么
Show me what?
昨晚 我们把货放上铁索特
Okay, so, last night, we're loading up the last Tesotek…
离地约200哩 突然间…
we're about 200 miles above the ground, and then all of a sudden…
船上收到信号
The hauler picks up this beacon.
纳瓦洛追踪它 结果…
So Navarro tracks it, and it turns out…
有艘巨型威兰船舰在我们头上漂流
there's this big Wey-Yu ship drifting right above our heads.
漂流
Drifting?
退役 废弃了
Decommissioned. Abandoned.
残骸 大概受损或被淘汰了
Some old relic. It's probably damaged or obsolete.
就像那家伙
Like that guy over there.
比约恩
Bjorn.
好 告诉她吧
Okay, just tell her.
我们为何要坐在这里
Why are we all sitting around here…
等待公司永远不会发的旅行许可
waiting for travel permits that the company are never gonna give to us?
那艘船有动力带我们去伊瓦加星
'Cause that hauler has enough power in it to get us to Yvaga.
因为到伊瓦加星要九年
Because it takes nine years to get to Yvaga…
没有冻眠就到不了
and you can't make that trip without cryo-sleep.
退役船还载着许多可用装备
Decommissioned ships still carry tons of functional equipment.
超链接显示那艘船还剩几个冻眠舱
And the hyperlink shows that ship still has a few pods left.
你们想闯入威兰的船
You want to break into a Weyland-Yutani ship
偷走高度管制装备
and steal highly regulated equipment?
捷足先登啊
Before someone else does.
你们疯了
You guys are insane.
当然 -才怪
- Well, of course we are. - No. No, we're not.
这是… -我也这么说
- This is… - That's what I said.
你会帮我们吗
Are you gonna help us?
抱歉 需要我做什么
Sorry, what do you need me for?
安迪
Andy.
我们需要用到安迪 -安迪
- We need to use Andy. - Andy?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
他是威兰合成人 能跟母亲沟通
He's a Weyland-Yutani synthetic. He speaks Mother.
他能进入船上的终端机
He can access a terminal on the ship to get us in
让我们轻松进出
and out without a fuss.
只有那样才能进去
It's the only way to get in.
要是我们被逮到呢
Okay, but what if we get caught?
获得旅行许可的机会就没了
It'll ruin our chances of ever getting a travel permit.
好 小雨不去
Right, Rain's not comin'.
不然你让我们带安迪去
How about you let us take Andy then?
我才不让我弟自己上去
I'm not sending my brother up there alone.
他不是你弟吧
He's not your brother though, is he?
比约恩 给我闭嘴 -没错啊
- Bjorn, shut the fuck up. - It's true, though, isn't it?
他不是你弟 只是威兰的瑕疵品
He's not your brother. It's just Wey-Yu damaged goods…
你爸在垃圾里找到的
that your dad found in the trash.
如此而已 认清现实吧
And that's all he is, Rain. So just wake up.
我们走
Let's go.
小雨 -怎样 我又没说什么
- Rain? - What? I didn't say anything.
小雨 等等
Rain, wait.
抱歉 我表弟有时很机车
I'm sorry. Listen, I know my cousin can be a dick sometimes, all right?
可是他说对了一件事
But he is right about something.
你得认清现实
You need to wake up.
这家公司什么都不会给我们
Because this company, they're not gonna give us anything.
你也明白我们只能放手一搏
You know that as well as I do. We have to take it.
小雨 我…
Rain, I just…
我不想落得跟我们爸妈一样
I don't want to end up like our parents.
你想吗
Do you?
你们的计划有听起来那么容易吗
Is it as easy as you're making it sound, this plan of yours?
你根本不必离开科布伦号
You won't even have to get out of the Corbelan.
这点我能保证
That much I can promise you, okay?
好啦 你愿意吗
Come on. What do you say?
比约恩 快 走了
Bjorn, hurry up, let's go.
好 我要发动了 启动电池
All right, I'm starting her up. Batteries on.
很好
Lovely.
给我看氢气引擎
Could I get hydro, please?
通讯控制台
Comm panel.
地面扰流板
Ground spoilers.
准备就绪
They are armed.
第一次上太空吗
First time in space, huh?
对
Yeah.
你也是吗
You too?
燃油汞
Fuel pump.
开启 -两个太空菜鸟来了
- On. - Two space virgins coming through.
好好看看窗外
Right, take a good look outside the window…
我觉得我们不会回来了
'cause the way I see it, we're never coming back.
还好吗
You good?
我很好
I'm good.
会很顺利啦
Yeah. It's gonna be all right.
现在还觉得这是好主意吗
Are you sure this is a good idea now?
当然 老爸
Sure, Dad.
强重力来了
Here comes the crush.
就是这样
That's how it's done, bitch.
那是…
Is that…
对
Yeah.
那是我们的太阳
That is our sun.
人家说伊瓦加星有绝美的夕阳
They say Yvaga has the most incredible sunsets.
我看过
I've seen them.
在梦里
In my dreams.
我等不及陪你一起看
I can't wait to see them with you.
嗯
Yeah.
听说冻眠会让好多年…
You know, I heard that cryo-sleep just makes years…
感觉像狂饮一夜
feel like one night of heavy drinkin' apparently.
等明天在伊瓦加星醒来
So when we wake up in Yvaga tomorrow…
我们就会宿醉
we'll wake up with a hangover.
在那里
There she is.
那不是船
That's not a ship.
不是
No.
好大 那是什么
Fuck, that's big. What is that?
退役的前哨站 不知道
Decommissioned outpost? I don't know.
应该是被拖进我们的轨道
Probably got dragged into our orbit.
纳瓦洛 麻烦靠近点
Okay, Navarro, let's get closer, please.
好 跟它同步旋转
Okay. I'm gonna match its roll.
（警告）
危险物接近警报
Hazard proximity alert.
怎么了
What's wrong?
小行星带比我想的近了一点
It's just the belt's a bit closer than I thought.
距离多远
How long?
差不多36小时
It's 36 hours, give or take.
距离什么
Till what?
太空站撞上小行星带
Before the station crashes against the rings.
抱歉 什么
Sorry, what?
你说什么 听起来不妙
What did you just say? That doesn't sound very good.
36小时
36 hours.
我们进出只要30分钟
We should be in and out in 30 minutes.
对吧
Yeah?
安迪
Andy.
顶多
Yeah, tops.
你确定要这么做吗
Are you sure you wanna do this?
我只有一项指令
I have just one directive.
为小雨的最佳利益着想
To do what's best for Rain.
你爸写的
Your dad wrote it.
对
Yeah.
还有一堆冷笑话
That and too many dad jokes.
我很乐意…
I'm happy…
协助
to help.
到那边要小心
Be careful out there.
快点 两分钟后对接
Okay, hurry up. We're docking in two minutes.
穿上
Put that on.
为什么要穿这个
Now, why I gotta put this on for?
你的蛋蛋才不会冻坏
So you don't freeze your balls off.
别再扯到我的蛋蛋 不健康
Mate, you gotta stop obsessing about my balls, man. It's unhealthy.
再说我就把它们切掉
Keep talking and I'll chop 'em off.
原来是你自己很哈
Aw, you really want 'em for yourself, don't you?
要看我的蛋蛋吗
Hey, you want me to show you my balls or something?
给我闭嘴
Oh, shut up a minute.
拿手套
Gloves, here, take these.
不行 别乱碰
Hey! No. Stop touching shit.
过来 -比约恩 别烦他
- Come over here. - Bjorn, leave him alone, for fuck's sake.
安迪 别理他
Andy, take no notice.
他弄坏东西与我无关
All right, okay, won't be my fault when he breaks somethin'.
前面有合成舱门 我要对接了
There's a synth hatch right ahead. I'm gonna dock.
收到 慢慢过去
Copy that. Just bring us in slow.
靠 里面超冷
Oh, fuck me, it's cold in there.
那是什么
What's that?
温度扫描仪
It's a temp-scanner.
能带我们去找冻眠舱
It's gonna lead us to the pods.
压力够
Okay, compression is good enough.
氧气太稀薄 无法呼吸
Oxygen is too thin to breathe.
安迪
Andy…
换你
you're up.
该表现一下了
It's your time to shine.
赞 安迪
Yes! Andy!
漂亮
Beautiful work.
好
Okay.
恭喜 你破处了
Congrats. You're not a virgin anymore.
好
All right.
走吧
Okay, let's go.
靠
Fuck.
我们应该进入零重力状态了
Guys, it looks like we're in zero-g.
我的肚子感觉得到
Yeah, I can feel it in my stomach.
那是什么
Wait, what's that?
重力产生器
Gravity generators.
离线后仍定时自我清除
When offline, they still purge themselves every few minutes.
以免这里爆炸
Prevents the place from blowing up.
靠 我肚子又有感觉了
Oh, fuck me, there goes my stomach again.
好 正前方
Okay, straight ahead.
根据扫描仪 冻眠舱应该在这里
According to the scanner, the pods should be in here.
天啊
Jesus.
安迪 还好吗
Andy, you good?
还好
Yeah.
好消息 我看到冻眠舱了
All right, great news. I've got eyes on the pods.
靠
Fuck!
比约恩 还好吗
Bjorn, you okay?
靠
Fuck!
我屁眼裂开了
I think I fractured my asshole.
重力清除不是闹着玩的
Fuckin' hell. Don't fuck with this gravity purge, man.
（系统启动）
幸好这残骸里还有电
Thank God, there's still some power left in this relic.
（氧气复原）
（重力产生器上线）
小心 重力回来了
Okay, watch out. Gravity's coming back.
他妈的
Fuckin' hell.
好 来吧
All right, here we go.
看这里有什么
Let's see what we got.
好
Okay.
（3.2年）
可恶
Shit.
什么问题
What's the problem?
冻眠舱燃料不足
Pods don't have enough fuel.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他们装了停滞三年用的燃料
They're loaded up for three years in stasis.
可是到伊瓦加星要九年
Yeah, but it takes nine years to get to Yvaga, mate.
我知道 我明白
Yeah, I know, I know. I'm aware of that.
他妈的
Fuckin' hell.
我知道 我就知道
I knew it. I fuckin' knew it.
我就知道 -别激动
- I knew it. - Just relax.
也许你们应该回来
Maybe you guys should just come back.
还不能放弃
No, no, we're not givin' up now.
伊瓦加星是最近的系统
Yvaga's the nearest system.
现在该怎么办
So what are we supposed to do now? Huh?
怎么办 -闭嘴
- What are we gonna do? - Shut up.
读数很强 一定是附近的冷冻仓库
Okay, strong reading. Must be a cryo depot nearby.
那里应该有更多燃料
We should find more fuel there.
纳瓦洛 我要弹射紧急逃生艇
Navarro, I'm ejecting the EEV.
过来 安迪
Come on, Andy.
你们接逃生艇 我们找燃料
You guys pick it up while we get the cryo-fuel.
等等
Hold.
四百码外 正前方
Yeah, 400 yards away, dead ahead.
干嘛用军人的口令
What's with the military shit?
什么 -你刚说的那些
- What? - All that military shit.
效率高 -是吗
- Well, it's effective. - Is it?
又很酷 -才怪
- And cool. - It's not very cool.
你看起来很蠢
You just look like a twat.
对不起 -别激动
- I'm sorry. - All right, chill.
继续前进
Let's keep it movin'.
再这样我扁你
If you do that again, I'll fuck you up.
比约恩 别闹了 -懂吗
- Bjorn, back off! - You understand?
只要他别来惹我
Just as long as he stays out of my way.
他干嘛对他这么坏
Why is he being such a dick to him?
因为发生在他妈身上的事
Because of what happened to his mom.
什么意思
What do you mean?
上个周期 矿区瓦斯外泄
Last cycle, there was a gas leak in the mines…
有个合成人决定封闭矿区
so a synthetic made the call to seal
但比约恩的妈妈还困在里头
them with Bjorn's mom still trapped inside.
什么
What?
合成人不能伤害人类
Synthetics can't harm humans.
为了救十几个人 牺牲了三名矿工
It sacrificed three miners to save a dozen.
他们可以那么做
That, they can do.
太可怕了
That's terrible.
（紧急逃生艇弹射启动）
（注意 弹射）
进来…
I got you, I got you.
快啊…
Come on, come on, come on.
（货物舱）
慢慢来
Easy, easy.
非常好
Good job.
小凯
Kay!
Kay! Hey, hey, hey.
嘿…
Hey, hey, hey.
我在这里 没事
I'm right here. I'm right here. You're okay.
我去看看冻眠舱
I'm gonna go check on the pods.
不 别担心
No, no. Don't worry.
我没生病
I'm not sick.
那是怎么回事
What's wrong, then?
没事
Nothing is.
天啊
Oh, girl.
孩子的爸是谁
Who's the father?
一个混蛋
Some asshole.
别告诉我哥 好吗
Just don't tell my brother, okay?
他烦恼够多了
- He has enough things to worry about. - No.
我不会说
I won't say anything.
我很高兴这宝宝能见到太阳
I'm just happy this baby will get to see the sun.
（威兰企业 打造美好世界）
应该快到了
I think we're almost there.
好 纳瓦洛
Okay, Navarro.
5B气锁室 找到燃料后就从这里出去
Airlock 5-B, that's our way out once we find this cryo-fuel.
马上过去
On my way.
欢迎莅临文艺复兴太空站
Welcome to the Renaissance Space Station…
威兰研发中心
the center of Weyland-Yutani Research and Development.
本站分成两部分
The station is divided into two halves…
罗穆路斯与雷穆斯
Romulus and Remus…
各自致力改善人类在外太空中的角色
each dedicated to our quest to improve mankind's role in outer space.
这里害我起鸡皮疙瘩
This place gives me the creeps.
听过有矿工失去左半边吗
Did you hear about the miner who lost his left side?
他现在是右翼分子
He's all right now.
懂吗 他是右翼分子
Do you get it? He's all right.
你能关闭自己吗
Can you turn yourself off, please?
你说你很紧张
You said you were nervous…
我想让你… -天啊
- and I was trying to make sure you were… - Jesus!
我等不及要进冻眠舱
You know, I can't wait to get in them pods…
再也别见到你 懂吗
and never see you again, you know that?
你在伊瓦加星会见到我
You'll see me in Yvaga.
你没有要去伊瓦加星
No, you're not going to Yvaga.
比约恩 别说了
Bjorn, stop!
真的吗
I'm not?
算你狠
Well done.
她没告诉你吗
Oh, she didn't tell you?
对 那是非威兰系统
Yeah, yeah, it's a non-Weyland-Yutani system…
不准有假人
so no fake people allowed.
我偏好用「人造人」
I prefer the term "artificial person" myself.
安迪 听好
Andy, look.
小雨带着你可能会坐牢
Rain could end up in prison if she takes you with her.
如果你们待在杰克森星
And if you guys stay in Jackson, it's just a matter of time…
你迟早又会被公司停用
before you get decommissioned again by the company.
懂吗
You understand?
你在船上看守冻眠舱
I need you on the ship to guard the pods.
等我们到那里…
But once we get there…
停用
Decommish.
永久关闭
Lights out for good.
说完了吗
You done?
实话实说而已
Just tellin' the truth.
没关系
That's okay.
对小雨好就是对我好
If it's what's best for Rain, it's what's best for me.
你是好人 安迪
You're a good guy, Andy.
我们会想你的
We're all gonna miss you.
所以他不知道
So he didn't know?
我就是不忍心告诉他
I just did not have the heart to tell him.
你不必难过
You shouldn't feel bad.
可恶
Shit.
别为了安迪浪费一辈子
You're not gonna throw your whole life away for Andy's sake.
他不在乎 那对他不重要
He doesn't care. It doesn't matter to him.
他不…
Okay? He's not…
不是真的
you know, real.
讯号来自这里
The signal's coming from in here.
你不是说这里停用了
Thought you said this place was decommissioned.
对
Yeah.
看起来不像
Doesn't look decommissioned to me.
没错
No, it doesn't.
但确实遭到弃置
But it's definitely deserted.
安迪 你看
Hey, Andy, look at this.
用这个应该能电死合成人
I could probably fry a synthetic with one of these…
只要我增强电力
if I just amp up the juices.
我可能带这个走
Hey, you know, I might take this with me, actually.
够了
All right, enough.
以免你有什么怪念头
Just in case you have any fucking funny ideas.
玩笑 我开玩笑的
It's a joke. I was joking.
搞屁啊
What the fuck?
小心
Watch out.
靠
Shit.
只是个合成人
It's only a synthetic.
靠
Fuck.
我差点以为是真人
I thought it was a real person there for a second.
那里发生什么事
What happened in there?
不知道 也许是化学物质外泄
Don't know. A chemical spill, maybe.
燃料一定在那房间 我们拿了就走
The fuel must be in that room. Let's grab it and get the fuck out of here.
（冷冻室）
好 安迪
All right. Andy?
比约恩 请拿手电筒
Bjorn, take the torch please.
（冷冻燃料 危险）
我觉得这里没有冻眠舱
I don't think there's any pods in here.
只是冷却设备 用同样的燃料
Nah, just cooling equipment. Uses the same type of fuel, though.
太好了
Yes.
45公斤
Forty-five Ks.
到伊瓦加星绰绰有余
It's more than enough fuel to get us to Yvaga.
比约恩 麻烦帮我一下
Right. Bjorn, give me a hand with this, please.
比约恩 数到三往外拉
Bjorn, pull it out on three, all right?
准备好了吗
- Ready? - Uh-huh.
一 二…
One, two…
三
three.
靠
Fuck!
靠 -我的手指
- Fuck. - My fingers.
我手指没感觉了
I can't feel my fingers.
好痛 我的手冻坏了
It really hurts. Just froze my hands off.
怎么了 -靠
- What's happening? - Fuck.
不知道 某种紧急封锁
Don't know. It's some kind of emergency lockdown.
安迪 开门
Andy, the door.
（请联络科学官）
他没有权限
Shit, he doesn't have the clearance.
什么意思
What does that mean?
没有开门的权限
Doesn't have the clearance to open the door.
你是说他能重启整艘船
So you're trying to tell me that he can fucking reboot the entire ship…
却不能打开一个普通房间的门
but can't open a random fucking door to a random room?
显然那不是普通的房间
Well, obviously, that's no random room.
快啊
Come on!
放心 我们会救他们出来
Hey, don't worry. We'll get 'em out of there.
如果安迪打不开 我们应该也没辙
If Andy can't open those doors, I doubt we'll have better luck.
他是威兰合成人
He's a Weyland-Yutani synthetic…
我们这是非法入侵
and we're just trespassing.
对 有什么想法吗
Yeah, so you got any ideas?
还没
Not yet.
我想在这里
I think it's in here.
比约恩
Bjorn!
泰勒
Tyler!
他们在里面
They're in there.
你在干嘛
Hey, what are you doing?
如果这个模组还能用
If this module is still working,
我想传它的凭证给安迪
I can try to transfer its credentials to Andy.
更高的权限应该能开门
A higher clearance should open that door.
（标本完成 打印暂停）
可恶 卡住了
Shit. It's stuck.
这里面好热
It's so hot in here, man.
（X光灯 贴紧身体使用）
哇
Whoa.
超赞
Sick.
别乱碰这里的东西
Yeah, maybe try not to touch anything in here.
好 老妈
Yeah, okay, Mom.
快帮我 帮我
Help me! Help!
糟糕 该怎么做
Oh, no! What do I do?
模组 拿出来
The module. Take it out!
你还好吗
You okay?
太奇怪了
That was fucked up.
拿去
Here.
我看看
Let me see.
对 好
Yes, okay.
好了
All right.
搞定 -嘿
- Got it. - Hey.
小雨
Rain.
从那个合成人身上取出的
This is from that synthetic.
放在安迪的模组上
Try putting it on Andy's module.
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我们离开这里吧
Let's just get outta here.
安迪
Andy?
试试看
All right, let's see.
好
Okay.
靠
Fuck.
小雨 我做错了什么 他不动了
Rain, did I do something wrong? He's just frozen up.
他在重开机
He's just rebooting.
需要几分钟
It's gonna take a couple of minutes.
我拿东西包扎你的手指
Here, let me get you something for those fingers.
那是什么鬼
The fuck was that?
在那边待一下子
All right, stay there a second.
泰勒
Tyler?
你们在做什么
Hey, what are you guys doing?
比约恩
Bjorn?
别闹了 快起来
Stop playing around, man. Just get up.
我没有 水里有东西
I'm not playing around. There's something in the water.
什么东西
What do you mean? What is it?
不知道 水里有东西
I don't know. I don't know what it is. There's something in the fuckin' water.
比约恩
Bjorn!
靠
Fuck!
那是什么
What the fuck was that?
安迪
Andy!
比约恩
Bjorn!
比约恩 快想办法救他
Bjorn, help him! Do something!
比约恩
Bjorn!
泰勒 -对不起…
- Tyler! - I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
快点
Come on!
快来帮我 -不要…
- Come on! Help me! - No, stop. Stop. Don't…
不 纳瓦洛 -那些东西会出来
- No! Navarro! - Those things will get out.
过来…如果它们过来…
If they come in here… If they come in… If they come…
不
No!
靠…
Fuck. Fuck.
安迪 我们走
Andy! Let's go!
快 比约恩
Go! Bjorn!
安迪 开门
Andy, the door!
比约恩 -快点
- Bjorn! - Come on, come on.
快点…
Come on, come on, come on!
（获准进入）
快出来 -快点…
- Get out of there! - Come on, come on, come on!
快… -快走
- Come on, come on, come on! - Go, go, go!
快出来…
Get out of there! Get out of there!
比约恩 快 -快走
- Bjorn, come on! - Go! Go!
安迪 关门
Andy, the door!
别动 -我知道
- Stay still. Stay still. - I know!
它掐住她了
It's choking her.
快住手
Stop! You gotta stop! Hey!
它掐住她了 -可恶
- It's choking her! - Shit.
住手 比约恩
Stop! Bjorn!
比约恩 快住手
Bjorn, stop! For fuck's sake, stop!
住手 -它要杀死她吗
- Stop! - What's it doin'? Is it fuckin' killin' her?
我认为那不是它的目的
I do not believe that's what the creature is doing.
不是
No.
安迪
Andy?
根据那些囊的扩张节奏
Based on the rhythmic dilatation of those bladders…
而且与她呼吸模式同步
and its synchronization to her breathing patterns…
我猜它在输氧给她 让她活命
I'd surmise it's feeding her oxygen to keep her alive.
但我不知道用意何在
For what purpose, I do not know.
你到底是谁
Sorry, who the fuck are you?
我是ND255威兰合成人
I'm an ND-255 Weyland-Yutani synthetic.
为执行采矿与安全任务而建造
Originally built for mining and safety tasks.
你们都叫我安迪
You guys call me Andy.
是那个模组
It's that module.
对
Yes.
新模组不只升级我的凭证
That new module didn't just upgrade my credentials.
还大幅升级我的人工智能
It substantially updated my AI…
此时也在修补我的运动系统
and it's mending my motor systems as we speak.
逾期许久的升级
A most overdue upgrade, I must say.
我要烧死这东西 -等等
- Shit. I'mma fucking fry this thing. - Okay, wait.
不要 -为什么
- Don't! - Why not?
那么强的电流会使它尾屈肌严重收缩
That amount of current will violently contract its tail flexors…
弄断她的脖子
and will break her neck.
你有更好的办法吗
So what, you got a better idea?
不然怎么办
What should we fucking do then, huh?
安迪 你知道怎么救她吗
Andy, do you know how to help her?
可惜我的知识库并未改变
I'm afraid my knowledge database has not really changed.
我不知道这是什么生物 如何移除它
I do not know what this creature is or how to remove it safely.
但现场有人可能知道
But there's someone in this room who might.
（合成人员A2系列）
（上线：卢克科学官）
我需要守护Z01化合物
I need to secure Z-01 compound.
这是优先任务 其他任务取消
Mission's priority. All other priorities rescinded.
必须完成此任务
Must complete the mission.
抱歉
I'm sorry…
你的任务失败了
but your mission has failed.
什么 不 我…
What? No, I…
你能告诉我们如何救她吗
Can you tell us what we can do to help her?
不要救她 快跑
You don't help her. You run.
不管你们怎么进来 快离开
Get out, however you got in.
不…等一下
No, no, no. Wait, whoa, whoa.
我们不会丢下她 你懂吗
Nah, we're not fuckin' leavin' her, okay? You understand?
那就大发慈悲 马上结束她的生命
Then have mercy and end her life now.
否则 你们都会死
If not, you all die.
他究竟在说什么
So what the fuck is he sayin'?
它在对她做什么
What's it doing to her?
这只拟寄生物将破胸体植入她体内
The parasitoid is implanting the Plagiarus Praepotens in her.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
一个种子 将与她DNA结合
A seed that will amalgamate with her DNA
迅速从她体内长出来
and rapidly grow out of her.
她体内会长出什么
What's gonna grow out of her?
XX121异形
XX121 Xenomorph.
20年前我们拖船首次接触这种标本
One of our towing ships first made contact with this specimen two decades ago.
诺史莫号上七名成员 只有一人幸存
Of the seven crew members aboard the USS Nostromo, only one survived…
将那生物炸出气锁室
blowing the creature out of the airlock.
此后我们一直在寻找它
We've been searching for it ever since.
170天前 我们的研究终止
170 days ago, our search came to an end…
异形的身体被带上船
and the body of the Xenomorph was brought on board…
推测已死亡
presumed dead.
当然
But of course…
缺少氧气和食物对这种完美生物…
lack of oxygen and food is of no true consequence to this…
影响不大
perfect organism.
但没有什么是真正不死的
Yet nothing is truly immortal.
显而易见
Clearly.
它大肆破坏这座太空站
It wreaked havoc over this station…
直到我们剩下的安全部队射杀它
until what was left of our security forces shot it dead.
却触发它的告别演出
Only to trigger its swan song.
酸性血液
Acid for blood?
硫酸和氢氟酸
Sulfuric and hydrofluoric.
我再次封锁太空站 但为时已晚
I sealed the station back up, but it was too late.
闭嘴
Hey, shut up!
已经没人在乎你的船了
Nobody cares about your fucking ship anymore.
好…
Okay, okay. Okay.
如果用冷冻燃料冷冻尾巴根部呢
What if we use the cryo-fuel to freeze the root of the tail?
如果结冻 它就无法掐住她
Maybe if it's frozen, it won't choke her.
可能有用
That could work.
把它拿下来
All right, get it off! Get it off!
它走了 放开你了
It's gone. It's off of you. It's off of you.
走了…
It's off. It's off. It's off.
你没事了
You're okay. You're okay.
我不会这么笃定
I wouldn't be so sure.
概率有多少
What are the odds?
六成概率对你们朋友不利
60 to 40 against your friend.
什么概率
What are the odds on what?
那只怪物已完成任务
That the creature's finished its job already.
他在说什么
What is he talking about?
听我说
Listen to me.
人类必须经历太多情绪阶段
Humans go through too many emotional stages…
才能接受冷酷但理性
before accepting the cold,
有时最艰难的途径
yet rational - sometimes hardest - path.
你必须帮他们
You must help them.
安迪
Andy?
怎么了 -对不起
- What's going on? - I'm sorry…
不能让她回到船上
but we can't let her back on the ship.
那就麻烦了 -你在干嘛
- Oh, yeah? That is a problem. - What're you doing?
你必须了解
- You must understand. - You see?
什么怪念头 -你在说什么
- That's what I mean by "funny ideas"! - What're you talking about?
不…
No, he's…
不… -他妈的烂咖
- No! No! - You fuckin' bitch!
安迪…
Hey! Andy! Andy!
我们走
We're gonna go.
我在这里
Hey, hey, hey! I'm right here.
我们走 快点
Let's go, let's go. Come on.
泰勒 我们快走
Tyler, let's go, man! Come on!
我在这里 -比约恩 不
- I'm here. - Bjorn! No.
比约恩 不能丢下她
Bjorn, we're not leaving without them!
我在这里 -比约恩
- I'm here. - Bjorn!
他们在哪 -注意听
- Where are they? - You need to listen.
快去发动船 -小雨呢
- We have to start the ship, okay? - Where's Rain?
快去发动船
Just go and start the ship.
原谅我
Forgive me.
我一直是你的负担
I've been nothing but a burden to you.
今天我终于能帮忙
Today, I can finally help.
你不会再把我当小孩了
And you won't see me as a child anymore.
什么
What?
安迪
Andy!
（基因实验室 冻眠实验室）
嘿 -比约恩
- Hey! - Bjorn!
靠…
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
纳瓦洛 解除对接
Navarro, undock!
让船脱离
Undock the ship!
（解除对接）
Undocking initiated.
开始解除对接
气锁室请净空
Please clear the airlock.
他在干嘛 不能丢下我们
What the fuck is he doing? They can't just leave without us.
他觉得安迪想杀死纳瓦洛
He thinks Andy's trying to kill Navarro.
什么
What?
是吗
Wait, is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
安迪 安迪
Andy? Andy?
安迪 开门
Andy, open the door.
抱歉 我阻止不了他
I'm sorry. I couldn't stop them.
比约恩
Bjorn?
你在干嘛
Bjorn, what are you doing?
你不能丢下我们 回来接我们
You can't just leave us here. You gotta come back and get us.
抱歉 她得先关闭那个神经病
Sorry, I can't do that until she turns that psychopath off.
怎么了
What's going on?
安迪…
Andy…
安迪失灵了 -什么
- Andy, he's glitchy. - What?
我得马上离开这间气锁室
I just need to get away from this airlock right now.
我需要…
I just need…
纳瓦洛
Navarro?
你还好吗
Are you all right?
怎么了 你需要什么
What's wrong? What do you need?
纳瓦洛
Navarro?
天啊
Oh, God.
天啊 那是什么
Oh, my God, what is that?
纳瓦洛 拜托 纳瓦洛
Navarro, please. Navarro! Navarro!
喂…
Hey, hey, hey.
我不知道怎么办 对不起
I don't know what to do, I'm sorry. I don't know.
快说话
Someone talk to me!
小凯 比约恩 纳瓦洛 怎么了
Kay, Bjorn, Navarro, what's going on?
救命啊
Help!
救命啊 -小凯
- Help! - Kay!
怎么搞的
What's happening? What's happening?
拜托别让我死
Please don't let me die.
（警告 燃料）
快来人啊
Someone help!
（罗穆路斯机库区2号）
比约恩
Bjorn?
小凯
Kay?
我们得去找他们
We have to go get them.
倒数47分钟发生撞击
T-minus-47 minutes to impact event.
完全不合理
Doesn't make any sense.
我以为你说有好几小时
No, I thought you said we had hours.
爆炸使太空站的轴线偏移了几度
The explosion pushed the station's axis off by a few degrees…
造成提早撞击小行星带
just enough to hit the asteroid belt a lot sooner.
他们撞上哪里
Where did they crash?
罗穆路斯机库区 在太空站另一边
Romulus Hangar Bay, on the other side of the station.
好 -我们走
- Okay. - Let's go.
倒数45分钟发生撞击
T-minus-45 minutes to impact event.
（输入存取密码）
母亲 Z01化合物的完整性如何
Mother. What's the integrity of Compound Z-01?
（储藏完整性）
还有希望
There's still hope.
我们得设法到罗穆路斯舱
We need to find a way to cross to the Romulus module.
不…
No, no, no.
它们一定是从实验室向外扩散
They must've spread from the lab.
没别的路了
I don't see another way.
安迪…
Andy, can…
我脑中听到你的声音
I heard your voice in my head.
在呼唤
Calling.
ND255人造人
ND-255 artificial person.
你这个型号曾是我们移民行动的支柱
Your model was once the backbone of our colonization efforts…
很荣幸能见到你
and it's an honor to be in your presence.
请容我自我介绍
Please allow me to introduce myself.
我是卢克科学官
I'm Science Officer Rook…
现在恳求你提供服务
and I humbly request your services now.
可是我只有一项指令
I'm afraid I have just one directive.
为了最佳利益…
To do what's best for…
你升级后有了新指令
Your upgrade came with a new directive.
它会覆盖旧指令
It overrides the old one.
了解
I see.
是什么要求…
What's required of me…
长官
Sir?
完成我们的任务
To finish our mission.
安迪 -安迪
- Andy! - Andy!
安迪
Andy.
很抱歉
My apologies.
我在为我们的状况请教朋友
I was consulting my friend about our situation.
跟我来
Follow me.
我们的状况 你…
What? Our situation? How do you…
安迪…
Andy! Andy!
这些拟寄生物没有眼睛
The parasitoids have no eyes.
它们靠声音追踪你 但主要靠热信号
They track you by sound, but primarily, by heat signature.
什么
What?
你的体温
Your body temperature.
好
Right.
如果提高室温到与体温相同
If we raise the temperature in the room to match our bodies…
它们就看不见我们吗
would that make us invisible to them?
如果我们够安静的话
If we're quiet enough?
只有一个办法能知道
Just one way to find out.
嘿
Hey.
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
没错
Yeah, it is.
你的 我的 大家的错
Yours, mine, and everyone else's.
我们决定一起行动的
We all decided to do this together.
我们会找到他们的
We'll get to them.
倒数40分钟发生撞击
T-minus 40 minutes to impact event.
（危急）
走廊温度目前与你们的体温相同
The hallway's temperature is now equal to your bodies…
那些生物应该看不见你们
so the creatures should not be able to see you.
但压力 恐惧和恐慌会使体温上升
But stress, fear, panic will spike your temperature…
你们就会曝光
and you'll be exposed.
汗水 鸡皮疙瘩
Sweat, goosebumps.
那是皮肤试图让身体降温
That's your skin trying to cool your body down.
请留意那些反应
So watch out for those.
保持冷静与安静
Now, stay calm and stay quiet.
快啊…
Come on. Come on!
Come on! Come on!
好了
Okay. Okay.
比约恩 我们走
Bjorn, let's go. Let's go.
靠
Fuck!
拜托别过来
Stay back, stay back, please.
靠
Fuck!
不 靠
No! Fuck!
泰勒
Tyler.
快啊
Come on.
小凯
Kay…
天啊 泰勒
Oh, my God, Tyler…
小凯 我在这里
Kay, I'm here. I'm here.
泰勒 拜托救我
Please, Tyler, help me.
大家都死了 我门打不开
Everyone's dead. I can't open this door.
拜托
Please.
有红色按键的控制杆
The lever with the red button…
左边有钥匙
there's a key to the left.
救命啊
Help.
我找不到
I can't find it.
没有钥匙 泰勒
There's not a key. There isn't a key, Tyler.
在那里 一定在
It'll be there. It has to be there.
钥匙 好
A key. Okay, okay.
我找到钥匙了
I have the key. I have the key.
天啊
Oh, my God.
快跑
Run.
Go! Go!
快跑
Wait!
等等
快啊
Come on!
你差点害他进不来
You almost closed the door on him.
对 但并没有
Yes, but I didn't.
我精准计算时间 比上次成功
I calculated the timing perfectly with more success than last time.
你们不同意吗
Won't you agree?
它们快接近了
We're getting close.
我们快走
Let's move.
（罗穆路斯机库区）
倒数30分钟发生撞击
T-minus 30 minutes to impact event.
（罗穆路斯 雷穆斯）
拒绝存取
Access denied.
小凯
Kay…
我们在这里 没事…
We're here. We're here. It's all right, it's all right, it's all right.
安迪 开门
Andy, open the door.
没事
It's all right.
我们会救你出来
We're gonna get you out.
泰勒 开门
Tyler, open the door.
快开门
Open the door. Come on.
天啊
Oh, my God.
看着我 小凯 -安迪 开门
- Look at me. Kay, Kay, Kay. Look at me. - Andy, open the door.
小凯 看着我 我会救你出来
Kay, look at me. Look at me. It's all right. I'm gonna get you out.
安迪 开门 别闹了 -你干嘛
- Andy, open the door. Stop fucking around. - What are you doing?
别看那边
Don't look over there.
安迪
Andy.
泰勒 怎么了
Tyler, what's wrong?
你马上开门 懂吗
Hey, I need you to open that door right now, okay?
那只怪物就等着我们开门
That's what the creature's waiting for us to do.
拜托快打开
Open it, please.
安迪 开门 -听我说
- Andy. Andy, open the door. - Listen to me. Listen to me.
她怀孕了 -拜托 快点
- She's pregnant. - Just, please. Guys, please. Come on.
她要生宝宝了
She's gonna have a baby. Okay?
听到了吗
Do you hear what I'm saying?
开门两秒 关门又要两秒
It takes that door two seconds to open, another two to fully close.
你们在干嘛
What are you doing? What are you doing?
快啊 你们在干嘛
Come on, what are you doing? Please…
那样足够让怪物进来
That's plenty of time for the creature to get in here.
拜托…快开门
Please, please, please open the door.
你们怎么不救我
Why won't you help me?
听我说
Listen, listen.
拜托救我 -你得赶快跑
- Come on, help me, please. - You have to run right now.
拜托 -快跑
- Please, please. - Run. Run.
你也是队员 -只能这样
- You're one of us, man. You're one of us! - Kay, it's the only way.
快开门 安迪 -你快跑
- Open the fucking door. Andy! - You have to fucking run.
懂吗 -安迪 拜托
- All right? - Andy, please!
只能这样 -安迪
- It's the only way. - Andy!
你快跑 -拜托
- You have to run! - Please!
给我开…
Open the fucking…
小凯
Kay! Kay!
No, no, no.
小凯
Kay!
我来开
I'll open it.
她没事 她在动
She's all right. She's moving.
没事
No. It's all right.
安迪 拜托开门
Andy, open the door, please.
安迪 我得进去救她
Andy, I need to go and get her.
真的很抱歉
I'm truly sorry.
我实在没办法救她
There was nothing I could have done to save her.
你他妈的可以开门的
You could have opened the fucking door!
那样我们都会死
We'd all be dead if I had.
我们得趁怪物进来前离开
We need to move before the creature finds its way into this room.
安迪
Andy…
你的最高指令是什么
what's your prime directive?
我有了新指令
I'm afraid I have a new directive.
为公司的最佳利益着想
To do what's best for the company.
我得拿掉那个模组
I need to remove that module.
那不符公司的最佳利益
I'm afraid that's not in the best interest of the company.
我们该走了
We need to move.
马上走
Now.
你怎么能那样
How could you do that?
怎样
What?
丢下人们不管
Leave someone behind?
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
完成卢克托付给我的任务
To finish a task Rook has entrusted upon me.
完成后他会准许科布伦号离开
When completed, he'll clear the Corbelan for departure
打开对接区的门
and open the docking bay doors.
你们能继续前往伊瓦加星
You will be free to continue to Yvaga together.
我会回杰克森星
And I'll return to Jackson.
留在杰克森星
And stay in Jackson.
假设我们能活着离开的话
That is, assuming we make it out of here alive.
（罗穆路斯实验室）
我们到了
We're here.
罗穆路斯贝塔实验室
Romulus Beta Lab.
全体人员均需A1安全许可
All personnel require A-1 security clearance.
那是什么
What is that?
应该是某种邪恶的生物武器
Probably some fucked up bio-weapon, I'm sure.
其实正好相反
Actually, quite the opposite.
安迪 告诉他们
Andy, tell them.
把我的话告诉他们
Tell them what I told you.
我们的殖民地奄奄一息
Our colonies are dying.
极端温度 每个周期都有新疾病
Unbearable temperatures, novel diseases every cycle.
有毒的矿区烟雾
Toxic mine fumes.
出乎意料的惨况一再发生
It's all one unforeseen tragedy after the other.
人类根本不适合太空殖民
Mankind was never truly suited for space colonization.
他们太不堪一击
They're simply too fragile.
他们太脆弱
They're too weak.
本站企图改变这一点
The work of this station aimed to change that.
人类应该是完美生物才对
"The perfect organism." That's how we should refer to human beings.
所以 我纠正这个错误
So, I set this wrong right.
我为了人类利用它的天赋
I took its gift for humanity.
我在异形DNA改造的拟寄生物体内
Inside the parasitoids I bioengineered from the Xenomorph's DNA…
发现了违反牛顿粘性定律的独特液体
I discovered a unique non-Newtonian fluid.
生命
Life.
最原始纯粹的型态
In its most primal, unadulterated form.
这种微生物可能是
This microorganism can be
已知最具破坏力的病原体
the most destructive pathogen ever observed.
但在实验室经过乙酰化与合成后
But acetylated and synthesized in our lab…
我将它变成威兰先生梦寐以求的奇迹
I've turned it into the miracle Mr. Weyland died searching for.
普罗米修斯之火
Prometheus fire.
给人类的神圣献礼
The divine gift to humanity.
Z01含有能让异形…
Z-01 contains the genome responsible…
任意加速与减缓代谢的基因组
for the Xeno's ability to accelerate and slow down its metabolism at will.
它的共生能力可透过血液
Its symbiotic capableness easily rewrites
轻易改写宿主的DNA
the host's DNA through its blood.
（自动注射器）
这是人类亟需且迟来的升级
This is a much needed and well overdue upgrade for humanity.
我们再也不能等待演化了
We simply cannot wait for evolution anymore.
我们能离开了吗
Yeah, can we get out of here now?
我的任务是带这个回殖民地继续发展
My mission is to take this back to the colony for further development.
卢克在追踪化合物
Rook is tracking the compound.
在船上侦测到后 他就会打开对接区
When detected inside our ship, he'll open the docking bay doors…
设定货船为自动驾驶 回殖民地
and set the hauler on autopilot back to the colony.
等等
Wait.
你看到了吗
Do you see it?
那边
There.
那玩意在猎杀我们
The fucking thing's huntin' us.
好 新计划
Right. New plan.
（开启）
你有办法用枪吗
Can you manage yourself with a gun?
当然可以
Yes, I fucking can.
这是F44AA脉冲步枪
Right, this is an F44AA pulse rifle.
转动式闭锁 电磁脉冲
It's rotating breech, electronic pulse action.
是殖民地陆战队用枪
It's what the Colonial Marines used.
AA代表瞄准辅助
AA stands for Aiming Assist.
好 放在手臂下面
So, right, you put that under your arm.
对 这只手放这里
That's it. Right, this hand here.
瞄准安迪
All right. Aim it towards Andy.
扳机扣一半
Pull the trigger halfway.
放心 上了保险
Don't worry, the safety's on.
看吧
See?
瞄准辅助
Aiming assistance.
如果那玩意过来
If that thing comes towards you…
对准它的方向就不会失手
you point it in its general direction, you'll never miss.
你在哪学的
Where'd you learn all this?
游戏和杂志
Games and magazines.
你只有一个弹匣
You've just got one mag. That's it.
450发
450 rounds.
一枪都不能发射
And you mustn't fire a single one.
酸性血液 记得吗
Acid for blood. Remember?
我们在太空站底层
We're on the bottom floor of the station.
脚下是太空真空
Below our feet is the vacuum of space.
射杀那只怪物
You shoot that creature…
保证立刻失压
and it's a guaranteed instant decompression.
我们都会没命
And we all die.
那给我们枪干嘛
So what's the point in giving us the guns?
怪物可能把它当成威胁
Because the creature may see it as a threat…
或许不会正面攻击我们
and maybe won't charge at us dead on.
或许
Maybe.
概率很高
Big maybe.
我发现一条输送带通道
I found us a way through the conveyor belt.
走这边
This way.
安迪
Andy.
你在吗
Are you there?
倒数20分钟发生撞击
T-minus 20 minutes to impact event.
走廊底有电梯
There's a lift at the end of this corridor.
能直接送我们到船上
It will take us directly to our ship.
那些东西还有更多
There's more of those things.
对 不妙
Yeah, that's not good.
它们似乎在这里一段时间了
They seem to have been here for quite some time.
安迪
Andy?
天啊
Jesus Christ.
忙碌的小怪物
Busy little creatures.
我们最好回头找别的路
I think we better go back and find another way.
这主意不错
That might be a good idea.
安迪 看能否打开这道门
Andy, see if you can open this gate.
站住
Stop.
怎么了
What?
小凯
Kay!
嘿
Hey!
泰勒
Tyler!
小凯
Kay!
找到她了
I got her, I got her.
没事 我们救你
It's all right. We got you.
她没死
She's alive.
我们救你下来
Okay, we got you, we got you.
等等
Hold on.
好
Okay.
我们在这里
We're here, we're here.
泰勒 她流了很多血
Tyler, she's losing a lot of blood.
或许这样才没被植入
Maybe that's why she hasn't been implanted yet.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
她脚边没有死掉的拟寄生物
There's no dead parasitoid by her feet.
安迪 这要怪你 你想办法
Andy, this is on you. So you do something.
拜托 安迪
Please! Andy!
人类25%的基因组与老鼠相同
25% of the human genome is shared with rats.
它对老鼠有用
And it worked on the rat.
来 小凯
Come on, Kay.
不要
Don't.
我有什么选择
What choice do I have?
我们带她回货船 放进冻眠舱
We take her back to the hauler and we put her in the cryo-pod. Okay?
维持她的生命 回殖民地接受治疗
That will keep her alive long enough to get her proper treatment back at the colony.
我不相信这个
I don't trust this.
安迪 她撑得住吗
Andy, will she make it?
如果动作快的话
If we hurry.
快走…
Go! Go!
我看到了 -这里
- I see it. I see it. - This is it, this is it.
我扶她…
I got her. I got her. I got her.
你没事
You're okay. You're okay.
好惊险
We're so close. We're so close.
嘿 你没事
Hey. Hey, you're okay.
我们快到了…
Hey, we're almost there. We're almost there.
就差一点点
You see, you're so close.
你要撑下去
You just gotta hang in there.
小心
Watch out!
泰勒
Tyler?
Tyler!
你只有这点能耐 只有这招
Is that all you got? Is that all you got?
安迪
Andy!
不 泰勒
No! Tyler!
小凯 听我说
Kay, Kay, listen to me, okay?
电梯直通我们的船
This goes straight to our ship.
你注射这个 进入冻眠舱
I need you to take this. And get into a cryo-pod.
自动驾驶会载你回殖民地
And autopilot will fly you back to our colony.
你做得到吗
Can you do that?
可以吗
Yes?
那你呢
What about you?
我会想办法回去
I'll find a way back.
（上）
让我拿出来
Let me take it out.
我会把你修好
And I'll fix you in return.
听我说
Listen to me.
你在这里会死
You'll die in here…
那不符公司或我的最佳利益
and that's not in the best interest of the company or mine.
快点 安迪 拜托
Come on. Andy, please.
倒数10分钟发生撞击
T-minus 10 minutes to impact event.
小雨
Rain?
安迪
Andy.
我很抱歉 -不
- I'm so, so sorry. - No, no.
不 我才抱歉
No, I'm sorry.
拖延它们不了多久
It won't hold them off for long.
快啊
Come on.
你是在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
（罗穆路斯实验室）
喂…拜托帮我们
Hey. Hey. Please help us.
开门
Open the door.
我得驳回你的请求
I'm afraid I must deny your petition.
我不能冒险危及Z01化合物
I just can't risk compromising the compound.
但我很感激两位给予公司
But know that I'm grateful for the invaluable help…
无价的协助
you two have provided to the company.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch!
安迪 开门
Andy, open it.
来 -打开
- Here. - Open.
没用
It's not working.
可恶
God damn it!
我不能骗你们概率有多少
I can't lie about your chances…
但我同情你们
but you have my sympathies.
（远端）
按下去
Press it…
我才能控制你的船 带你飞离
so I can take control of your ship and fly you out of here.
你是谁
Who are you?
朋友
A friend.
你的同伴死了 好让你存活
Your companions died so you could live.
按下按键
Press the button…
让我确保他们不会白白牺牲
and let me honor their sacrifice.
安迪 你能说个笑话吗
Andy, can you tell me one of your jokes?
怪物为什么不吃小丑
Why don't monsters eat clowns?
尝起来很好笑 -尝起来很好笑
- 'Cause they taste funny. - They taste funny.
我搞不懂复制
I don't understand cloning at all.
我跟你一样
That makes two of us.
我看过一本讲零重力的好书
I read a great book about zero gravity.
我放不下来 -放不下来
- I just couldn't put it down. - Couldn't put it down.
小雨
Rain?
小雨 你要干嘛
Rain, what are you doing?
我要关闭重力产生器
I'm turning off the gravity generator.
十…
Ten…
九 八 七
nine, eight, seven…
六 五
six, five…
四 三
four, three…
二 一
two, one.
（关）
小雨 你确定吗
Rain, are you sure about this?
只有一个办法能知道
Only one way to find out.
成功了
It works.
小雨
Rain!
你还有40%
You're at 40%.
20%
20%.
小雨
Rain!
操
Fuck.
待在我后面
Stay behind me.
安迪 小心
Andy, be careful.
小雨
Rain!
安迪 还好吗
Andy, you okay?
我们得到电梯那边
We need to get to the elevator.
（下次重力清除 系统倒数）
电梯没重力就无法运作
The elevator won't work without gravity.
准备好了吗
Ready?
小雨
Rain!
靠
Fuck.
不
No.
是重力清除
It's a gravity purge!
（开）
安迪
Andy!
快点
Come on.
安迪
Andy!
离她远一点
Get away from her.
你这个贱货
You bitch.
撞击倒数十…
Impact event in 10…
九 八
nine, eight…
七 六
seven, six…
五
five…
四 三 -快点
- four, three… - Come on.
二 一
…two, one.
小凯
Kay.
你怎么这么久
What took you so long?
我带你离开
Let's get you outta here.
（MU/TH/UR要求远端接管）
很高兴你们俩活着
I'm glad to see you two made it.
（MU/TH/UR接管）
（冻眠舱超眠系统）
小心头
I got you. Watch your head.
谢谢 -你们没事了
- Thank you. - You're gonna be just fine.
母子都是
Both of you.
公司对今天的成就感到无比骄傲
The company couldn't be prouder of what's been accomplished here today.
我已传信息回总部
I've sent a message back to HQ.
半年后收到后 他们会前往杰克森星
When received in six months, they'll travel to Jackson's Star…
接收Z01化合物 做进一步研发
to retrieve the compound from you for further development.
（手动驾驶 自动驾驶）
你在做什么
What are you doing?
（MU/TH/UR断线）
改变计划
Change of plans.
安迪 阻止她
Andy, stop her.
立刻重新连线
Reconnect us now.
不…你们不能这么做
No, no, no. You two cannot do this.
Z01化合物必须交给公司
The compound must be delivered to the company.
我必须驳回你的请求
I'm afraid I must deny your petition.
祝你今天愉快
Have a nice day.
你们两个最好听我说
Now you better listen to me here, now, you two.
你们在大计划下微不足道…
You are insignificant in the great scheme of things. You…
（清除）
不
No.
这让你系统保持连线 直到伊瓦加星
This will keep your systems online until we get to Yvaga.
我以为… -我不管
- But I thought that… - I don't care.
你跟我走 好吗
You're coming with me. All right?
只要符合小雨的最佳利益
If that's what's best for Rain.
安迪 我给你一项新指令
Andy, I have a new directive for you.
为我们的最佳利益着想
Do what's best for us.
没问题
Done.
很好
Good.
（生命征象危急 停滞中断）
糟糕
No.
小凯
Oh, Kay. Kay.
怎么了
What's wrong?
惨了…
Oh, no, no.
把它抓走
Get it away from me.
（货物完整性受损）
（自动驾驶断线）
（手动驾驶）
（货斗开启 离线）
天啊
Oh, my God.
小凯
Kay.
不 求求你
No. Please, please.
安迪…
Andy! Andy!
不…
No, no, no.
小雨…
Rain. Rain.
救她
Help her.
不
No!
安迪 快点
Andy! Come on!
拜托起来
Please get up!
不
No!
快点
Come on!
（室温危急）
（货斗开启 上线 拉控制杆启动）
手动解开货物 拉四根控制杆
"Manual Cargo Release. Pull the four levers."
好 四根控制杆
Okay. Yes. The four levers. Okay.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
（拉所有控制杆以解开）
爬升…
Pull up. Pull up.
去死吧 妈的贱货
Die, motherfucker!
（手动 自动驾驶）
（自动驾驶目的地：伊瓦加三号星）
我会修好你的
I'll fix you.
（人体冷冻声音日志）
这是采矿货船科布伦号的冷冻日志
This is the cryo-log for the mining hauler Corbelan.
我们前往伊瓦加星系 不知能否到达
I set course to the Yvaga system without knowing if I'll ever reach it…
或面临什么命运
or what fate is to find me.
无论如何 我都会面对
But whatever comes, I'll face it.
我是雨恩卡拉定
This is Rain Carradine…
科布伦号的最后生还者
last survivor of the Corbelan…
完毕
signing off.
《异形：罗穆路斯》
翻译：Aaron Wu